

Calvin McClure

Software Engineer

I am a software engineer with a background in software development, as well as network and system security. I am currently working on my Bachelors at Arizona State University and on track to graduate December 5th. Web and mobile app development is my strongest area of expertise but I am excited to expand my knowledge and spread into new roles!

CONTACT

Calvin McClure 623-363-3343 calvin.mcclure0917@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/calvin-mcclure

SKILLS

Web Development

Angular 1, 2 React Django **TypeScript** SQL / JSON Full Stack **App Development**

Java for Android

Swift

Software Enineering

C, C++, Java, PHP, Python

Cloud Storage

Google Cloud Storage Cloud Storage on AWS

Security

Computer Security **Network Security** Computer Forensics

AWARDS

CIW Javascript Specialist

CIW 2017

Best Web Application

www.codeday.org 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

XLR8 Development LLC Software Developer

Tempe, Oct 2017 - now

Pixingo Project Android App

2019-2020

FLO Project Django Website

2020-2021

Full stack engineer for a contract based web and mobile application development company. I have worked on projects with many different frameworks and for a range of platforms. In my role I have handled all aspects of a projects lifecycle. This includes, conversing directty with clients, working with teams, managing projects with different software engineering best practices, and testing.

Pixingo was an android app that I worked on with a partner at XLR8. I improved my front end skills with XML and the Android Studio layout editor. On the back end I used Java to communicate with APIs provided by the client and Firebase to deliver dynamic content. You can find this app on both the Apple and Android app stores but I only contributed to the Android version.

I have worked with many JavaScript frameworks but this was my first with python. Using a Python framework was a refreshing take on web that still used all the fundamentals im familiar with. One interesting thing about the project was my role in choosing and configuring the cloud blob storage implementation. This project also utilized a PostgreSQL database and a client provided API.

EDUCATION

Bachelor | Dec 2021 Computer Science (Cyber Sec)

Arizona State University | Tempe, AZ 2017 - 2021

West-MEC | Coding

West-MEC | Glendale, AZ 2015 - 2017

REFERENCES

Jaden Feddock Vice President XLR8 Development LLC 480-828-6398 jaden@xlr8dev.com

Brian Folk Manager Best Buy 623-202-4756